Anthony Lonsdale

(816) 872-7762 | alons3253@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/anthonymlonsdale

ABOUT ME

Holding a background in Physics and software development, I am committed to applying my expertise in the realm of Data Science. My problem-solving skills have been honed through various independent projects and three years of rigorous undergraduate research.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: TypeScript, Python, C#, C/C++, Excel VBA, LAMMPS

Web & Back-end: React, HTML/CSS, .NET, SQL

Tools & Platforms: Git, Visual Studio, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, AWS, Linux

Libraries & Frameworks: Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, scikit-learn, Openpyxl, Multithreading, Asyncio, Node.js

EDUCATION

Missouri University of Science and Technology

Rolla, MO

Bachelor of Science in Physics, 3.129 GPA

Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2022

Personal Projects

Algorithmic Trading Tool | Python, C#, C/C++, .NET

June 2020 - Present

- Developed a multi-language intra-day stock trading system, integrating Python, C#, C/C++, with a .NET backend.
- Applied advanced techniques like Trinomial Tree pricing for options arbitrage, Tick Data processing, adaptive algorithms and Risk management.
- Gained professional-level expertise in financial software engineering and multi-language software integration.

Achievements

- BSA Eagle Scout, Nationals qual. swimmer, 4x Speedo Sectionals Finalist, 4x MSHSAA All-State Swimmer.
- MO S&T Curators, Excellence, Chancellor's, Physics Department and Missouri Bright Flight Scholarships.
- Nat'l Science Olympiad Top-8 finalist, 3-yr regional Chem-a-Thon Top-4 finalist, ACS-Bayer Scholarship.
- 5x cash prize winner through 3.5 years of Undergraduate Research. Only student in Dept. with scientific paper.

EXPERIENCE

React Developer IT Intern/Data Engineer

May 2023 – October 2023

May 2022 – September 2022

ProMax Unlimited

Kansas City, MO

- Used React for front-end development of Stack, and implemented major new features in Desking client.
- Automated the generation and formatting of Excel workbooks with Python and C# by injecting VBA macros.
- Developed company-wide employee tabulation system and built advanced system mockups in Excel VBA.
- Presented demos to the executive board and software team, securing funding for major company projects.

Undergrad Research Asst. (Materials Physics)

September 2019 – December 2022

Missouri Univ. of Science and Technology

Rolla, MO

- Automated the submission, collection, analysis, and visualization for 4 discrete magnetized systems across the 10k-1000k temperature domain.
- Boosted Molecular & Spin Dynamics simulation run times using custom LAMMPS scripts.
- Pioneered Spin-Lattice simulation methods for Iron, Cobalt and Uranium Dioxide analogues.

Bernoulli Technologies LLC

February 2021 – Present

Founder, https://bernoullitechnologies.net

Liberty, MO

- Built Python scripts and used SQL backend for election visualization and voterbase analysis.
- Developed advanced modeling tools for increasing turnout using behavior data and analytics.
- Delivered 500k+ outreach messages for 25+ campaigns and PACs to date.